This episode we're going to be talking about sliding and diving.
Sliding and diving is very important because it is the fastest way that you can come from a full run to a full stop.
And also it's the best way that you can get behind some of the lower cover.
There's two basic kinds of slides.
You have the knee slide, and you have the headfirst slide.
We're going to talk about the knee slide this time.
Knee sliding is very much like in baseball, in that when you go into your cover, you're going to go in low, you're going to keep one knee bent, the other leg is going to be straight, and you're just going to come to a complete stop on the bent knee.
Sometimes you can also come to a complete stop on your hip as well--it's kind of a little bit of a preference thing.
It also depends on how low to the ground you need to be.
Another type of slide is a two knee slide that you see a lot more in paintball events.
And that is you come at a full run, and you basically break down on both knees, slide on both knees to the behind cover.
The advantage to this is, with a two knee slide, you can actually come up shooting, and in fact you can actually get into your slide and start shooting while you're sliding.
It's an advantage.
It's something that you can use on the field.
Which slide do you use?
Do you use a baseball knee slide?
Do you use a two knee slide?
It depends on what you're doing, what bunker you're getting into, and how fast you need to get from one place to another.